Marcus Wiberg

Berlin, Berlin, Germany



hi@marcuswiberg.com



linkedin.com/in/marcuswiberg

Summary

I'm a Swedish/American serial entrepreneur with a passion for solving exciting problems with unique and intuitive experiences where the customer is in the front seat.

I have built platforms used by millions of people, supported cancer patients with therapy through medical products, and built several startups from scratch.

Experience



Founder

SnapSound

Dec 2018 - Present (1 year 10 months +)

Add music to your videos & photos.

- # 4.8 review score on the AppStore from 177 ratings (globally)
- # Built a community of students to accelerate growth and feedback in regions abroad.
- # Designed the UX & UI and AppStore Connect assets for 34 different languages.
- # Gold Winner of international business award Stevie Awards 2019.
- # Shutdown by SoundCloud August 2019.

- Senior Product Owner

LivingPackets

Oct 2019 - 2019 (3 months)

Sustainable and convenient packaging for the e-commerce industry.

- # Launched the first products for iOS and Android.
- #I led cross-functional teams and improved software development processes.
- # CES 2020 Innovation Awards Honoree and Green Alley Award 2019.
- # Platforms: iOS, Android, Web, and Embedded software.

mika Head of Product

Mika

Jun 2019 - 2019 (7 months)

Driven by the vision to improve the well-being and therapy outcomes of cancer patients. In cooperation with the Charité, the University Hospital Leipzig, and the NCT Heidelberg (National Center for Tumor Diseases) Funded by https://ananda.vc/

- #Iled a team of designers, researchers, and acted as a product manager.
- #I lead our scrum initiatives (standup, sprints, retros, grooming, estimations)

Platforms: iOS, Android, and Web.

Head of Product

Matmatch

Mar 2018 - 2019 (1 year 10 months)

Matmatch helps you find, evaluate, and source the best materials for your industrial projects.

Trusted by more than 2 million engineers and designers.

Demo: https://vimeo.com/246770278

- #I led a team of designers, researchers, and acted as a product manager.
- #I lead our scrum initiatives (standup, sprints, retros, grooming, estimations)
- # Conducted workshops and lead cross-functional teams.
- # Interview about my work at Matmatch https://matmatch.com/blog/how-matmatch-is-continuously-enhanced/

Senior Product Manager

Matmatch

Oct 2017 - Mar 2018 (6 months)

- # Handover of product from Boston Consulting Group Digital Ventures (BCGDV)
- # Product manager of internal and external tools.
- #I lead our scrum initiatives (standup, sprints, retros, grooming, estimations)

Founder | Product

Switchplace Sverige AB

Sep 2015 - May 2017 (1 year 9 months)

Real estate platform established to tackle the growing demand for apartment swapping in Sweden.

Demo: https://vimeo.com/153559746

- #I co-founded the company with designers, developers, and a marketing agency.
- #I led a team of designers, researchers, and acted as a product manager.
- # Built a community with thousands of registered apartments in Sweden.
- # Platforms: iOS, Android, and Web.

S Founder | CEO

Socialmist AB

Sep 2010 - Jan 2017 (6 years 5 months)

Socialmist was a social networking platform with music from SoundCloud.

Demo: https://vimeo.com/283530006

- # I raised ~2.4M USD in funding by Swedish and American investors.
- # Reached Top 10 on the App Store (Category: Social networks)
- # Built a strong community of young people to accelerate growth and user feedback.

Signed partnership with VS model Kelly Gale & launch events with Kygo https://vimeo.com/157730641 https://vimeo.com/153559591

Managed 25 full-time employees (mostly engineers, designers, and product managers)

Platforms: iOS, Android, and Web.

Founder

MW Ventures

Sep 2010 - Jan 2017 (6 years 5 months)

Supporting startups with product development and strategy.

Education



Academy for Academic Excellence

High School Diploma, English Language and Literature

Sjölins Gymnasium

High School Diploma, Business/Managerial Economics

Kunskapsgymnasiet (Gothenburg, Sweden)

High School Diploma, Communication and Media Studies

Licenses & Certifications

G Google Analytics For Beginners - Google

Issued Aug 2018 - Expires Aug 2020

G Advanced Google Analytics - Google

Issued Dec 2019 - Expires Dec 2021

Google Analytics for Power Users - Google

Issued Dec 2018 - Expires Dec 2020

Skills

Entrepreneurship • Start-ups • Product Management • Agile Methodologies • Product Development • User Experience • Mobile Applications • Software Development • Business Strategy • Marketing Strategy